<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>/Home/AlaskanTF - Journal of a Pleb</title>
    <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T20:32:29+08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Why Linux is My Daily Driver Now</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-linux-is-my-daily-driver-now/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-linux-is-my-daily-driver-now/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/Screenshot_20250821_201728.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Tech Tools"/>
            <category term="Privacy Journey"/>

        <updated>2025-08-21T18:37:05+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/Screenshot_20250821_201728.png" alt="BASH!" />
                    My First PC - The Compaq Presario My fahters Compaq Presario with Windows 95 - Not original image but exactly how it looked I have&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/Screenshot_20250821_201728.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="BASH!" /></p>
                <h2>My First PC - The Compaq Presario</h2>
<figure class="post__image align-center" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="outline: 3px solid rgba(var(--color-primary-rgb), 0.55) !important;" src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/compaqpresario.jpg" alt="Compaq Presario running Windows 95" width="889" height="500" sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/compaqpresario-xs.jpg 300w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/compaqpresario-sm.jpg 480w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/compaqpresario-md.jpg 768w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/compaqpresario-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<figcaption >My fahters Compaq Presario with Windows 95 - Not original image but exactly how it looked</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I have been around computers for as long as i can remember<span style="color: #e03e2d;">*</span>. The first PC i ever touched was a Compaq Presario running Windows 95 with a 56kbps dial-up connection. I can still hear the sound of the modem connecting like it was yesterday. At that time, the internet was still young as was I. It was a vast uncharted world and the PC was my gateway into it. From internet explorer browsing random sites to flash games to hanging out on telnet BBS (bulletin board system) to simple coding, learning how drivers worked, thinkering with things and some curious hacking (shuting down teacher's PC remotely using CMD, making some "small" changes to the school's website). Those early days sparked a deep curiosity in me about how the systems operated but mainly how they could be manipulated.</p>
<p>*I'm not that old, I just started young.</p>
<h2>The Lead Up to Using Linux</h2>
<p>Fast forward a few years, I started exploring other OSes (Operating Systems) such as Linux and the many distros (Distributions) such as Debian, Fedora, Ubuntu, Arch, PopOS! etc. Since then, I have always had a dual-boot setup, Linux system as my secondary boot as I always fall back to Windows as their GUI (Graphical User Interface) always made things easier and also for better gaming compatibility. However, over the years, Linux has really improved in all departments, from GUI to gaming support (some games even perform better on Linux now).</p>
<p>As I grew older and followed how the internet and technology has grown. The internet that was once an open space for freedom, sharing and exploration isn't what it used to be anymore. It's has became a place for data harvesting, targeted ads and constant surveillance. The more i found out how it all works, the more i wanted to protect my own data and also help others do the same. With that said, that's how my privacy journey began.</p>
<h3>Digital Minimalism to Privacy Advocate</h3>
<h6>Minimalism</h6>
<p>A few years ago, I noticed that I spent hours just playing mindless games on my mobile phone, doom scrolling social media and checking my notifications very few minutes. I decided it was time to try out digital minimalism for a few months. I challenged myself to remove unnecessary distractions, which meant deactivating the few social media accounts I used only keeping Instragram to connect with friends and to occasionally see what they're up to. No more than 1 hour of use per day.</p>
<p>Doing this, I have actually freed up time and space for deeper and more meaningful interactions with technology and even the people around me. What I thought was an experiment for a few months lasted longer than expected. I never went back to social media again.</p>
<p>Sidenote: Now that I use my mobile phone less, I notice how much people are using theirs during dinners and meet-ups, it's <strong>FUCKING</strong> annoying. Might as well just hangout on Discord.</p>
<h6>Privacy Advocate</h6>
<p>During my digital minimalism journey, I also realized how much information and data we give away without thinking about it. From sharing everything we do to tracking cookies to social media surveillance. The technology that I once loved for connecting has evolved into exploiting us. We have became the product of these mega corporations, profiting off our data.</p>
<p>That was when I decided to dive into the world of privacy advocacy, learning about data encryption, VPN's and opensource tools that would help secure my data and minimize my digital footprint. This lead me to moving away from big tech such as Google, Amazon &amp; Microsoft etc. Obviously, there is no way to 100% avoid them, but it'll try my best to minimize contact. That's also the driving reason I have moved away from Windows and made Linux my main OS.</p>
<h3>Making the Switch</h3>
<p>I was lucky to have started tinkering with Linux since the early stages so I have some knowledge, making the learning curve less steep. However, Linux today is far more user friendly, it might even be easier to use than Windows now.</p>
<p>For over a decade, I have always kept Linux with me in a dual-boot configuration but it was always my secondary OS. As I started to embrace privacy more fully, I realized that Windows no longer align with my values. It's time to make Linux my primary OS and Windows my second boot option.</p>
<p>Why not just remove Windows completely? </p>
<p>The only reason I still keep Windows around is for gaming. Many games with strong anti cheat does not support Linux. So, I only boot into Windows then I needa game.</p>
<h3>Why Linux?</h3>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/Screenshot_20250821_201237.png" alt="My Fedora KDE Desktop" width="1920" height="1080" sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Screenshot_20250821_201237-xs.png 300w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Screenshot_20250821_201237-sm.png 480w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Screenshot_20250821_201237-md.png 768w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Screenshot_20250821_201237-lg.png 1024w">
<figcaption >My Fedora KDE Desktop</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As a privacy advocate, I now value privacy, autonomy and control over my data and digital life. Linux was the way to go.</p>
<p>After years of trying countless Linux Distros (Debian, Fedora, Ubuntu, Arch, Mint, Gentoo etc) with countless desktop environment (Gnome, KDE, Hyprland etc.).</p>
<p>All of these Linux distros has their own pros and cons but they have one thing in common: better privacy compared to Windows. Ultimately, I have chosen to settle down with Fedora KDE as it aligns with my values</p>
<p>Fedora KDE being opensource means I have full control over my system and security. I can see what's happening under the hood, no surveillance or data collection. My PC and data now belongs to me and me alone.</p>
<p>Also, most applications I use on Windows are available on Linux or an alternative exists. *More on this in another post.</p>
<p>TL;DR:</p>
<ul>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="7226" data-end="7259">Focus on Privacy and Security</strong><br data-start="7259" data-end="7262">Fedora support on free software and security was another big reason I chose it. Unlike Windows, where I had to fight to keep my data private, Fedora comes strong build in privacy tools and security features like SELinux, regular updates, and strong encryption support. Definitely a more secure environment for someone who values privacy.</p>
</li>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="6679" data-end="6720">Up to Date Software</strong><br data-start="6720" data-end="6723">Fedora always provides the latest stable software without all the unnecessary bloat that comes with other systems like Windows. I get cutting edge features and tools without compromising on performance or security.</p>
</li>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="6932" data-end="6957">KDEs Customizability</strong><br data-start="6957" data-end="6960">I can tweak everything from the look and feel of the desktop. This level of customization allows me to make the system my own, exactly how I want it to work and how I want my workflow to be</p>
</li>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="3300" data-end="3331">Telemetry &amp; Data Collection</strong><br data-start="3331" data-end="3334">As a privacy advocate, the amout of data Windows harvested even with privacy settings adjusted to the maximum, I knew there was no way to fully escape the telemetry and tracking. The amount of private things we do on our personal PC daily should remain only for us to know about.</p>
</li>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="3980" data-end="4009">No Bloatware &amp; Unwanted Apps</strong><br data-start="4009" data-end="4012">Windows seemed to be increasingly bloated with apps that I do not want or need. Things like OneDrive, Cortana, and other Microsoft services reminded me of how little control I have over my own PC.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">I have been using Fedora exclusively since the start of 2025 while only booting into Windows for gaming. I couldn't be happier.  My PC now respects my privacy, gives me full control, and works on my terms not on the terms of big corporations.</p>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">Check out <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Fedora Project</a> if you are interested.</p>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">Stay tuned for my future posts, perhaps on what privacy tools I use and what applications I use as an alternative if they are unavailble on Linux.</p>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">As usual, you know were to find me if you wanna join the privacy journey or have any questions regarding this topics.</p>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">Thanks for reading! :D</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why I choose full-time &quot;Unemployment&quot;</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-i-choose-unemployment/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-i-choose-unemployment/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/14/Screenshot_20250818_151032-2.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Reflections"/>
            <category term="In-my-opinion"/>
            <category term="Finance"/>

        <updated>2025-08-18T16:49:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/14/Screenshot_20250818_151032-2.png" alt="" />
                    Okay, it was supposed to be a short post, but I locked in and didn't notice I was typing so much. lol I've had it&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/14/Screenshot_20250818_151032-2.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Okay, it was supposed to be a short post, but I locked in and didn't notice I was typing so much. lol</p>
<h3>"Get a Real Job" Nonsense</h3>
<p>I've had it with these mfking people saying this mfking sentence: "Go get a real job."</p>
<p>When people and by people, I mean family and friends ask me "What do you do?" and I mention that I’m unemployed and prefer not to have a full time job, they often look at me like I'm batshit crazy. Well, sometimes I do think I AM crazy.</p>
<h3>Background Story:</h3>
<p>I was never the default citizen.</p>
<p class="msg msg--success">Study hard → get the paper → land a job → pay taxes → get married → buy a house → die.</p>
<p>In school, I was probably the “meh” below-average student. Things were too structured and boring. My answers would be marked wrong even if the final answer was correct because I used a different way to solve it. Most of the times, I just got it totally wrong lel. Still, I passed just enough to move on, which was fine by me. Not gonna waste my energy on something I'm not interested in,</p>
<p>After studies, like every generic citizen here, I served in the military. That went smoothly, nothing much to say. Then came university, where I majored in Economics. Again, just an average student. No "magna cum anything laude." LOL.</p>
<p><strong>So why Economics?</strong></p>
<p>Two words: <strong>Stock.</strong> <strong>Market.</strong></p>
<p>I always had an interest in the market since the Great Recession and the invention of Bitcoin in 2008–2009. (I was a computer geek, story for another post.)</p>
<p>I started trading/investing in equities in 2016. It’s like a video game: don’t run out of credits, and try to beat the high score. I LOVE IT.</p>
<h3>My Brief 9-to-5 Life and Epiphany</h3>
<p>After graduation, I went on a little soul-searching trip (backpacked and made many questionable financial choices), then got a job.</p>
<p>Every day, it was:</p>
<ul>
<li>"Looking" stressed about KPIs (which I didn’t take seriously, of course. I ain’t here to build your dream, I’m here to take your money and build mine.)</li>
<li>Useless micromanagement from clueless higher-ups who know shit and think "synergy" is a personality trait.</li>
<li>Wake up at 6:30am, work all day, then try to trade U.S. markets from 9:30pm to 4:00am.</li>
</ul>
<p>Remember people, life is too short to stress over nonsense because:</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight">If it can be done, get it done. If it can’t be done, why stress?</p>
<p>After some quick calculations, I realized I made about the same or more in the market compared to my day job (before taxes). And where I live, capital gains are <strong>non-taxable</strong>.</p>
<p>The 9-to-5 wasn’t just soul-sucking it was killing my portfolio. Trading the U.S. market (9:30pm–4:00am) while waking up at 6:30am to prep for work?</p>
<p><strong>My quality of life was:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sleep: <strong>Fucked</strong></li>
<li>Freedom: <strong>None</strong></li>
<li>Returns: <strong>Minimal</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>So I stayed there for a year since the pay was decent for a fresh grad, but really, I was just there to leech their money and fuck off which I did gracefully, like a polite thief. I added the earnings to my portfolio, gave it a nice boost, and never looked back.</p>
<p>Now, I am full-time unemployed, a job I love. Some days are chill, some are stressful AF. But:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rest when I want</li>
<li>Work at my peak hours</li>
<li>No one to bug me</li>
<li>Travel freely as long as I’ve got my laptop and internet</li>
<li>Watch a movie/game/chat with friends while monitoring markets on chill days</li>
<li>You get it.</li>
</ul>
<p>BTW, the stressful days are AWESOME! It keeps me in check, on my feet and prevent complacency.</p>
<h3>Salary VS My Unemployment</h3>
<p>Let’s base the numbers on a $100K annual income. You can change the numbers and the outcome would be the same as they are in percentages.</p>
<p><strong>Mr. 9-to-5 Salaryman</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Annual Salary: +$100,000</li>
<li>20% Sovereign Fund Contribution: -$20,000 (To be returned when? God knows, it keeps moving further away.)</li>
<li>17% Employer Top-up to Sovereign Fund: +$17,000</li>
<li>Income Tax: -$5,650</li>
</ul>
<p>Total Compensation: $100,000 + $17,000 = $117,000<br>Take-Home: $100,000 - $20,000 - $5,650 = $74,350<br>Locked in Sovereign Fund (aka Narnia): $37,000 (Growing at ~4% per annum)</p>
<p><strong>Me – The Allegedly "Unemployed"</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Annual Income: +$100,000</li>
<li>Sovereign Fund Contribution: -$0</li>
<li>Employer Top-up: +$0</li>
<li>Income Tax: -$0</li>
</ul>
<p>Total Compensation: $100,000<br>Take-Home: $100,000<br>Locked in Sovereign Fund: $0</p>
<p>Let's not forget about the power of compounding in the market.</p>
<p>Mr Salaryman would be getting $117000 per year.</p>
<p>The unemployedman would be getting ($100,000 + gain%) and then (total from previous year + gains%) repeated yearly.</p>
<p>That's just a rough calculation.</p>
<h3>But the Benefits! The Stability! The “Buy House!”</h3>
<p>According to the default citizens, they make $17,000 more than me and have $37,000 in the sovereign fund earning ~4% per year.</p>
<p>Here’s my POV: Yep, you made $17,000 more but your $37,000 is locked up until you either buy a house and empty it doing so, reach the ever shifting retirement age, or die and pass it to your kids.</p>
<p>I take home $25,650 more than you and reinvest it into a portfolio that returned ~80% annually (versus your fund’s 4%).</p>
<p>So being unemployed gives me more liquidity, no tax, and the freedom to top up my sovereign fund <strong>if</strong> I ever feel like buying a house. (CPF should never be reason for buying a house, unless you agree that you require someone a.k.a government to babysit your spending habits.) Either way, it's probably impossible to buy a house here without getting cuffed or locked down for life. But stability, ah, the illusion of it. We’ll get into that a little later.</p>
<h3>TL;DR – Why I'm Not Chained to a Desk</h3>
<p>I’m not unemployed because <strong>I can’t get a job</strong>. (I haven’t checked. Maybe I can't. LOL.)</p>
<p>I’m unemployed because <strong>I already have a job, </strong>one that:</p>
<ul>
<li>Pays well (in my opinion, really subjective)</li>
<li>No uncomfortable office wear</li>
<li>Unlimited breaks</li>
<li>More time with family and friends</li>
<li>Hobbies such as the <a href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/my-projects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">projects</a> i'm working on</li>
<li>Not taxed to oblivion (Income already taxed and our taxed income is than taxed again; GST, road tax, property tax etc. Cmon bruh.)</li>
</ul>
<p>So to everyone who keeps telling me to “get a real job”:</p>
<p class="msg msg--success msg--highlight msg--warning">I have one. It’s just not the kind you can flex on LinkedIn.</p>
<h3>Final Thoughts</h3>
<p>I’d agree stability is an issue. But I’ve never seen stability stop death from coming.</p>
<p>We plan, save, insure, and settle and then one day, we vanish. I’d rather live with uncertainty than die having played it safe.</p>
<p>Risk keeps me awake. The unknown keeps me on my feet. Security might help you live longer, but curiosity is what makes you feel alive now.</p>
<p>I’ve always believed in the present. The past is gone. The future might never come. So what else is there but now?</p>
<h4>Random thoughts:</h4>
<p>The government always says we have to work hard for the future generation, for the future of the country. But when exactly do we get to enjoy ourselves?</p>
<p>We build the present and live the present. Let the future generation build and enjoy theirs.</p>
<p>Because if every generation is only building for the next, here’s what happens: each generation ends up living off the previous ones and nothing truly progresses. It’s just sacrifice passed down like an heirloom, and nobody gets to celebrate. That's probably what all government wants, mindless people, under their control with the illusion of control.</p>
<p>Thank you for reading.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hello, world!</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/hello-world/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/hello-world/</id>
            <category term="Travel Journal"/>
            <category term="Tech Tools"/>
            <category term="Reflections"/>
            <category term="Privacy Journey"/>
            <category term="Guides/How-To"/>
            <category term="Gaming"/>

        <updated>2025-08-06T13:36:24+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Just a test post.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Just a test post.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
