<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>/Home/AlaskanTF - Journal of a Pleb</title>
    <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com" />
    <updated>2026-01-02T14:34:44+08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>2025 Fund Report - A Year in Review</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/2025-fund-report-a-year-in-review/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/2025-fund-report-a-year-in-review/</id>
            <category term="Finance"/>

        <updated>2026-01-02T13:53:44+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    DISCLAIMER: IM NOT A FINANCIAL ADVISER, I'M JUST A DELUSIONAL PLEB WITH NO IDEA WHAT THE FUCK I'M DOING. ANY POST ON THIS WEBSITE IS JUST MY PERSONAL OPINION ONLY AND A JOKE. NOTHING IS REAL. I AM A SCHITZO WHO INVESTS/TRADES IN HIS MIND AND THINKS HE RUNS A&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="msg msg--warning"><strong>DISCLAIMER:</strong> IM <strong>NOT A FINANCIAL ADVISER</strong>, I'M JUST A <strong>DELUSIONAL PLEB</strong> WITH <strong>NO IDEA WHAT THE FUCK I'M DOING</strong>. ANY POST ON THIS WEBSITE IS JUST <strong>MY PERSONAL OPINION ONLY</strong> AND A <strong>JOKE</strong>. NOTHING IS REAL. I AM A SCHITZO WHO INVESTS/TRADES IN HIS MIND AND THINKS HE RUNS A BLOODY FUND.</p>
<p>Dear Family &amp; Friends,</p>
<p>Thank you for the continued trust and support. As we close out 2025, I wanted to share a transparent review of the fund's performance, key decisions, lessons learned and how I'm thinking about the year ahead. This was one of the most volatile but rewarding year since the fund's inception. Despite sharp drawdowns driven by unexpected macro events, disciplined execution, emotional control and consistency in strategy resulting in a strong outcome.</p>
<hr>
<h3>2025 at a Glance</h3>
<p><strong>Fund Inception:</strong> 2023</p>
<p><strong>Strategy:</strong> U.S. equities combined with systematic call and put option selling</p>
<p><strong>Annual Performance</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>2023:</strong> +92.96%</li>
<li><strong>2024:</strong> +44.44%</li>
<li><strong>2025:</strong> +61.89%</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cumulative Return Since Inception: </strong>~+351%</p>
<p><strong>Max Drawdown (2025):</strong> -26.27%</p>
<hr>
<h3>Performance Summary</h3>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 25.6622%;"><strong>Year</strong></td>
<td style="width: 23.1109%;"><strong>Annual Return</strong></td>
<td style="width: 51.1671%;"><strong>Notes</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 25.6622%;">2023</td>
<td style="width: 23.1109%;">+92.26%</td>
<td style="width: 51.1671%;">Fund inception: Favourable market conditions</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 25.6622%;">2024</td>
<td style="width: 23.1109%;">+44.44%</td>
<td style="width: 51.1671%;">Continued compounding with increased option activity</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 25.6622%;">2025</td>
<td style="width: 23.1109%;">+61.89%</td>
<td style="width: 51.1671%;">Highly volatile year but with disciplined decisions</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 25.6622%;"><strong>Since Inception</strong></td>
<td style="width: 23.1109%;"><strong>~+351%</strong></td>
<td style="width: 51.1671%;">Compounded through reinvestment and consistency</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<h3>2025 Performance Review</h3>
<p>The fund delivered a <strong>61.89% return in 2025</strong>, improving meaningfully on 2024 returns and bringing the cumulative return since inception to ~351%. The results were achieved during a year marked by sharp market swings and elevated uncertainty.</p>
<p>The most challenging period was a <strong>26.27% drawdown</strong>, primarily triggered by unexpected tariff announcements that caused a rapid and broad based sell off in the market. While the decline was sudden, decisions were made not with emotions. Positions were reassessed rationally, premiums were made through selling of puts at peak panic, free cash and premiums were allocated, risk was managed and the portfolio was allowed to recover as volatility normalised.</p>
<p>2025 reinforced a core principle: process matters more than prediction.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Strategy and Execution</h3>
<p>The strategy throughout the year remained consistent:</p>
<ul>
<li>Accumulate high-quality U.S. equities</li>
<li>Selling <strong>cash-secured puts</strong> and <strong>covered calls</strong></li>
<li>Reinvesting option premiums and realised gains to compound capital</li>
</ul>
<p>The approach worked particularly well in a volatile environment. Higher implied volatility increase option premiums and rather than treating this income defensively, profits were actively redeployed to compound capital.</p>
<hr>
<h3>What Went Right</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Disciplined accumulation: </strong>Option premiums were consistently reinvest rather than sidelined.</li>
<li><strong>Emotional control:</strong> Volatile markets tested patience, but reactionary decisions were avoided.</li>
<li><strong>Active engagement:</strong> Staying close to the market allowed for better sizing and positioning.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3>What Could Have Been Better</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Over-hedging:</strong> Hedges were maintained longer than necessary in a bull market, increasing cost and reducing returns.</li>
<li><strong>Execution hesitation: </strong>In several cases, research conclusions were correct but hesitation prevented capital deployment leading to lowered returns.</li>
</ul>
<p>These lessons will directly inform future decision-making.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Market Environment</h3>
<p>2025 was shaped by policy uncertainty, tariff related headlines and quick sentiment shifts. Rather than attempting to predict or forecast macro outcomes, the focus remained on managing exposure rationally and using volatility as an input and not a reason to abandon the planned strategy.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Outlook for 2026</h3>
<p>Heading into 2025, the outlook is cautiously optimistic</p>
<p>Markets may continue to perform reasonably well but likely at a slower pace with ongoing volatility. The core strategy will remained unchanged, with a potential increment in allocation towards consumer staples as we monitor the cycles.</p>
<p>The goal remains to stay risk-aware without being blinded by short-term scares.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Closing Thoughts</h3>
<p>Since inception in 2023, the fund has compounded approx ~351% but not without volatility, mistakes or uncomfortable periods. This focus remains on maintaining a repeatable process, disciplined risk management and long-term compounding.</p>
<p>ALSO, we are comfortably above the high watermark. Unfortunately for investors and fortunately for me, that means another year of taking performance fees. All jokes apart, performance fees are only taken when the fund performs well and only on profits NOT capital. Therefore, our interests are aligned.</p>
<p>Thank you for the continued trust and support.</p>
<p>May 2026 be filled with bold goals, smart moves and success to all.</p>
<p>As always, I'm happy to discuss the fund in more details or answer any questions.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About My Portfolio (Plebs Capital)</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/about-my-portfolio-plebs-capital/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/about-my-portfolio-plebs-capital/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/17/bull-vs-bear-market.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Finance"/>

        <updated>2025-11-10T23:28:03+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/17/bull-vs-bear-market.jpg" alt="" />
                    DISCLAIMER: IM NOT A FINANCIAL ADVISER, I'M JUST A DELUSIONAL PLEB WITH NO IDEA WHAT THE FUCK I'M DOING. ANY POST ON THIS WEBSITE IS JUST MY PERSONAL OPINION ONLY AND A JOKE. NOTHING IS REAL. I AM A SCHITZO WHO INVESTS/TRADES IN HIS MIND AND THINKS HE RUNS A&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/17/bull-vs-bear-market.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p class="msg msg--warning"><strong>DISCLAIMER:</strong> IM <strong>NOT A FINANCIAL ADVISER</strong>, I'M JUST A <strong>DELUSIONAL PLEB</strong> WITH <strong>NO IDEA WHAT THE FUCK I'M DOING</strong>. ANY POST ON THIS WEBSITE IS JUST <strong>MY PERSONAL OPINION ONLY</strong> AND A <strong>JOKE</strong>. NOTHING IS REAL. I AM A SCHITZO WHO INVESTS/TRADES IN HIS MIND AND THINKS HE RUNS A BLOODY FUND.</p>
<h4><strong>1. Fund Overview &amp; Philosophy</strong></h4>
<h6 data-start="367" data-end="382"><strong data-start="367" data-end="380">The Story</strong></h6>
<p data-start="367" data-end="382">Plebs Capital was founded in 2022 out of a passion for financial markets and a belief that  investing should be accessible to everyone not just the rich, the accredited or institutional investors.</p>
<p data-start="367" data-end="382">My journey began in 2016, when I first entered the markets and lost nearly 90% of my savings due to being fucking dumb. That failure became my greatest teacher. After earning my B.A. in Economics and actively studying and understanding how markets truly work, I decided to put that knowledge into practice.</p>
<p data-start="895" data-end="1294">Starting with limited capital and the support of family and friends who believed in me, I started this portfolio, a fund built by and for everyday people (plebs). Managing money for others brought a new level of responsibility and discipline. Every decision I make is guided by one principle: to act in the best interest of the fund and its investors, focusing on sustainable, risk-managed growth.</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight " data-start="1296" data-end="1435"><strong data-start="1296" data-end="1318">Mission Statement:</strong><br data-start="1318" data-end="1321"><em data-start="1321" data-end="1435">Our mission is to empower everyday investors through disciplined, transparent, and performance-driven investing.</em></p>
<hr>
<h4 data-start="1442" data-end="1471"><strong data-start="1445" data-end="1471">2. Investment Strategy</strong></h4>
<p data-start="1442" data-end="1471">The portfolio is <strong data-start="1535" data-end="1574">60% visionary and 40% opportunistic</strong> focused primarily on <strong data-start="1598" data-end="1622">equities and options</strong>. This blend allows the fund to pursue long-term, high-conviction investments while maintaining tactical flexibility to capture near-term opportunities and manage risk while generating income.</p>
<h6 data-start="1794" data-end="2329"><strong data-start="1794" data-end="1822">Visionary Strategy (60%)</strong></h6>
<p data-start="1794" data-end="2329">The visionary portion targets companies that we believe will be <em data-start="1889" data-end="1940">needed and increasingly needed in the future.</em> We also analyse their supply chains, as growth in the primary company often drives growth in suppliers. For example, we identified NVIDIA (NVDA) at around $19 per share, recognizing that GPUs initially for gaming would become critical to AI as we saw their computing capabilities it had for mining Bitcoin. Anticipating NVIDIA’s expansion, we invested in key suppliers such as <strong data-start="2257" data-end="2272">Micron (MU)</strong> and <strong data-start="2277" data-end="2285">TSMC</strong>, capturing upside across the value chain.</p>
<h6 data-start="2331" data-end="2478"><strong data-start="2331" data-end="2363">Opportunistic Strategy (40%)</strong></h6>
<p data-start="2331" data-end="2478">The opportunistic allocation focuses on shorter-term, valuation-driven opportunities, primarily using options:</p>
<ul data-start="2479" data-end="2713">
<li data-start="2479" data-end="2543">
<p data-start="2481" data-end="2543">Waiting for favourable entry points when valuations are high.</p>
</li>
<li data-start="2544" data-end="2622">
<p data-start="2546" data-end="2622">Selling <strong data-start="2554" data-end="2562">puts</strong> to generate income or acquire stock at attractive prices.</p>
</li>
<li data-start="2623" data-end="2713">
<p data-start="2625" data-end="2713">Selling <strong data-start="2633" data-end="2650">covered calls</strong> on profitable holdings to lock in gains while managing risk.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p data-start="2715" data-end="2831">This hybrid structure allows the portfolio to remain adaptable while continuously compounding value for investors.</p>
<hr>
<h4 data-start="2838" data-end="2874"><strong data-start="2841" data-end="2874">3. Track Record &amp; Performance</strong></h4>
<p data-start="2876" data-end="3094">Since inception in 2022, the portfolio has a <strong data-start="2995" data-end="3033">total return of approximately 383%</strong>. The <strong data-start="3039" data-end="3067">2025 year-to-date return</strong> is currently <strong data-start="3081" data-end="3091">63.26%</strong>. ( as of 10 November 2025)</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/17/signal-2025-11-10-232004.png" alt="2025 YTD Performance of the fund" width="757" height="327" sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/17/responsive/signal-2025-11-10-232004-xs.png 300w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/17/responsive/signal-2025-11-10-232004-sm.png 480w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/17/responsive/signal-2025-11-10-232004-md.png 768w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/17/responsive/signal-2025-11-10-232004-lg.png 1024w"></figure>
<h6 data-start="3096" data-end="3272"><strong data-start="3096" data-end="3126">Key Drivers of Performance</strong></h6>
<p data-start="3096" data-end="3272">Returns have been driven by concentrated, high-conviction equity investments and tactical options strategies with no ETFs or passive funds.</p>
<h6 data-start="3274" data-end="3475"><strong data-start="3274" data-end="3299">Volatility and Vision</strong></h6>
<p data-start="3274" data-end="3475">The fund has experienced drawdowns of roughly <strong data-start="3348" data-end="3355">25%</strong>, reflecting the nature of visionary investing. Temporary declines are viewed as part of the long-term growth process.</p>
<h6 data-start="3477" data-end="3661"><strong data-start="3477" data-end="3500">Performance Mindset</strong></h6>
<p data-start="3477" data-end="3661">Beyond outperforming the market, the fund seeks to <strong data-start="3559" data-end="3592">beat its own previous results</strong>, fostering continuous improvement and disciplined decision-making.</p>
<h4 data-start="3668" data-end="3700"><strong data-start="3671" data-end="3700">4. Fund Structure &amp; Terms</strong></h4>
<ul data-start="3992" data-end="4104">
<li data-start="4066" data-end="4104">
<p data-start="4068" data-end="4104">SECRET! Investors will know ;)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h4 data-start="4111" data-end="4136"><strong data-start="4114" data-end="4136">5. Risk Management</strong></h4>
<h6 data-start="4138" data-end="4342"><strong data-start="4138" data-end="4177">Diversification and Position Sizing</strong></h6>
<p data-start="4138" data-end="4342">The fund maintains sector diversification and limits individual positions to <strong data-start="4257" data-end="4299">generally below 15% of portfolio value</strong>, balancing conviction with risk control.</p>
<h6 data-start="4344" data-end="4457"><strong data-start="4344" data-end="4377">Hedging and Market Protection</strong></h6>
<p data-start="4344" data-end="4457">Protective <strong data-start="4391" data-end="4399">puts</strong> are used to hedge against identified market-wide risks.</p>
<h6 data-start="4459" data-end="4635"><strong data-start="4459" data-end="4490">Liquidity and Cash Reserves</strong></h6>
<p data-start="4459" data-end="4635">Holding <strong data-start="4501" data-end="4536">10–30% of the portfolio in cash according to market sentiment</strong> allows flexibility to capitalize on opportunities and mitigate downside during market downturns.</p>
<hr>
<h4 data-start="4642" data-end="4677"><strong data-start="4645" data-end="4677">6. Future Outlook &amp; Strategy</strong></h4>
<p data-start="4679" data-end="4904">For 2026 and beyond, the fund focuses on identifying <strong data-start="4737" data-end="4777">companies at risk of being displaced</strong> and the innovators replacing them. The investment strategy remains unchanged, as it <strong data-start="4862" data-end="4901">scales effectively with growing AUM</strong>.</p>
<p data-start="4906" data-end="5083">While market direction cannot be predicted, the fund prioritizes <strong data-start="4971" data-end="5013">adaptability, research, and conviction</strong>, aiming to outperform both the market and its own previous results.</p>
<hr>
<h4 data-start="5090" data-end="5122"><strong data-start="5093" data-end="5122">7. Investor Communication</strong></h4>
<p data-start="5124" data-end="5412">Currently, updates are provided on request, but moving forward, the planned <strong data-start="5223" data-end="5244">quarterly reports </strong>which will be posted here will offer consistent insights into performance, portfolio composition, and strategic outlook.</p>
<hr>
<h4 data-start="5419" data-end="5455"><strong data-start="5422" data-end="5455">8. Disclaimer &amp; Risk Warnings</strong></h4>
<p data-start="5457" data-end="5695"><strong data-start="5457" data-end="5479">General Disclaimer</strong></p>
<p data-start="5457" data-end="5695">The fund is a privately managed investment fund for invited family, friends, and mutual acquaintances. This prospectus is for informational purposes only and does not constitute an offer to sell securities or to attract investors.</p>
<p data-start="5697" data-end="5882"><strong data-start="5697" data-end="5716">Investment Risk</strong></p>
<p data-start="5697" data-end="5882">Equity and options investments involve <strong data-start="5758" data-end="5778">substantial risk</strong>, including the potential loss of principal. Past performance is <strong data-start="5843" data-end="5879">not indicative of future results</strong>.</p>
<p data-start="5884" data-end="6037"><strong data-start="5884" data-end="5901">No Guarantees</strong></p>
<p data-start="5884" data-end="6037">The fund does <strong data-start="5918" data-end="5935">not guarantee</strong> returns or capital preservation. Risk management strategies cannot eliminate market risk or losses.</p>
<p data-start="6039" data-end="6239"><strong data-start="6039" data-end="6066">Investor Responsibility</strong></p>
<p data-start="6039" data-end="6239">Investors should consider their personal financial situation and risk tolerance before investing. By participating, investors acknowledge and accept the inherent risks.</p>
<p data-start="6241" data-end="6406"><strong data-start="6241" data-end="6271">Forward-Looking Statements</strong></p>
<p data-start="6241" data-end="6406">Statements regarding strategy or outlook are <strong data-start="6319" data-end="6338">forward-looking</strong> and subject to uncertainty; actual results may differ materially.</p>
<hr>
<p class="msg msg--info" data-start="6241" data-end="6406">Thanks for reading how I manage my portfolio. Perhaps in future posts, I'll further explain how I analyse and pick the stocks that I pick, how I handle losses, everything and anything that relates to investments and trading.<br><br>Let me know if there's anything you wanna know or have something discuss about.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How I Protect My Privacy Online: Tools and Steps</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/how-i-protect-my-privacy-online-tools-and-steps/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/how-i-protect-my-privacy-online-tools-and-steps/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/16/wp4564098.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Tech Tools"/>
            <category term="Privacy Journey"/>

        <updated>2025-09-20T20:00:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/16/wp4564098.jpg" alt="" />
                    Privacy isn't something that happens overnight. It's more of a process that requires continuous and consistent effort, regular adjustments, and a willingness to evaluate your online habits. As technology evolves, so do the methods of surveillance and data harvesting, meaning the steps we take today may not be enough tomorrow.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/16/wp4564098.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Privacy isn't something that happens overnight. It's more of a process that requires continuous and consistent effort, regular adjustments, and a willingness to evaluate your online habits. As technology evolves, so do the methods of surveillance and data harvesting, meaning the steps we take today may not be enough tomorrow. Thus, I say protecting your privacy is a continuous process that requires consistency. We must learn, adapt, and refine strategies to keep up with the ever changing landscape of privacy.</p>
<p>Before we dive into the specific tools I use</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning"><strong>DISCLAIMER:</strong><br>I am not a privacy professional. What works for me may not work for you, as each person's privacy needs are different depending on their threat model. For example, whistleblowers and journalists require a much higher level of privacy compared to someone who's just trying to hide their browsing habits or prevent large corporations from harvesting their data. Everyone's threat model is unique, so you will need to find the balance between privacy and convenience that works for you.</p>
<h3>My Threat Model</h3>
<p>Before starting your privacy journey, it's important to understand your threat model. To provide context for the tools and steps I use, here's an overview of my own threat model:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>What do I want to protect?</strong>
<ul>
<li>I am focused on protecting my personal data, such as browsing habits, communications, and sensitive information like passwords and health reports.<br><br></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Who do I want to protect it from?</strong>
<ul>
<li>Primarily, I want to protect myself from large corporations, surveillance, advertising networks, and data brokers. Additionally, I want to prevent data breaches from governments or corporations that may track my online behavior for political or commercial purposes.<br><br></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How likely is it that I will need to protect it?</strong>
<ul>
<li>I’m not dealing with high-risk threats like journalists or whistleblowers might face, but the amount of data being harvested and used for surveillance is enough to justify making some changes in my daily life.<br><br></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How bad are the consequences if I fail?</strong>
<ul>
<li>Failing to protect my privacy could lead to identity theft, loss of personal data, and manipulation (e.g., targeted ads, price manipulation). While these risks are manageable, I want to avoid them as much as possible.<br><br></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How much trouble am I willing to go through to try to prevent potential consequences?</strong>
<ul>
<li>I’m willing to put in consistent effort to protect my privacy. This means using privacy tools, privacy respecting applications, and sacrificing some convenience to reduce my digital footprint. However, it's all about balance, I'm not trying to reach a state of paranoia or extreme measures.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>You can read more about threat models here: <a href="https://www.privacyguides.org/en/basics/threat-modeling/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Threat Modeling: The First Step on Your Privacy Journey</a></p>
<h3>Privacy Tools I Use</h3>
<p>Now that we have an understanding of my threat model, let's take a look at the specific tools I use to protect my privacy. These tools help keep my data secure without compromising too much on convenience:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Operating System: <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Fedora 42 KDE</a> (instead of Windows)</strong>
<ul>
<li>I made a previous post about it. check it out <a href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-linux-is-my-daily-driver-now/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HERE</a>.<br><br></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Browser: <a href="https://www.firefox.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Firefox</a> with Privacy Extensions (instead of Chrome)</strong><br>The browser is one of the most important tools for privacy, as it's where I (and everyone) spend most of their online time.<br><br>
<ul>
<li><strong>Privacy Extensions</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>uBlock Origin</strong><br>A must have for blocking ads, trackers, and other unwanted content. It’s an effective and lightweight ad blocker that doesn’t compromise browsing speed.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Decentraleyes</strong><br>This extension reduces the reliance on third party servers by locally hosting common web assets like JavaScript libraries. This minimizes the amount of data shared with third-party websites.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>LocalCDN</strong><br>This extension serves common web resources locally, reducing the dependency on external content delivery networks (CDNs) that can track you across sites. It improves both privacy and performance.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Disable WebRTC</strong><br>WebRTC is a protocol for real time communication but can leak your true IP address, even when using a VPN. This extension ensures WebRTC is disabled, preventing that data leak.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Cookie AutoDelete</strong><br>This extension automatically deletes cookies when you close a tab, helping to minimize tracking from websites. It’s useful for keeping your browsing habits private.<br><br></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://nordvpn.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VPN: NordVPN</a></strong><br>NordVPN encrypts my internet traffic and routes it through a server, hiding my real IP address. It’s crucial for preventing surveillance and maintaining anonymity, especially when using public WiFi networks.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Password Manager: <a href="https://nordpass.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NordPass</a> &amp; <a href="https://keepassxc.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KeePassXC</a> (instead of Google/Apple/Samsung password manager)</strong><br>NordPass is used for securely managing my online passwords, while KeePassXC is my offline, self hosted password manager for sensitive information.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Cloud: Self-hosted NAS at Home (instead of Google Drive/OneDrive/Apple Cloud)</strong><br>Instead of relying on third-party cloud services, I use a self-hosted NAS (Network-Attached Storage) system at home. This gives me full control over my data storage and eliminates privacy risks associated with external providers.<br><br></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://proton.me/mail" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Email Provider: ProtonMail</a> (instead of Gmail/Hotmail)</strong><br>ProtonMail is a privacy focused email provider that offers end-to-end encryption (E2EE) and a no logs policy. It’s based in Switzerland, known for its strong privacy laws.<br><br></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://duckduckgo.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Search Engine: DuckDuckGo</a> (instead of Google)</strong><br>DuckDuckGo doesn’t track or store your search history. It’s a great alternative to Google, which profiles you based on your search activity.<br><br></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://getaegis.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2FA Manager: Aegis Authenticator</a> (instead of Google Authenticator/Authy)</strong><br>Aegis is an open-source two-factor authentication (2FA) codes manager. I use it to secure my online accounts by adding an additional layer of protection beyond just passwords.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Steps I Take Beyond Tools and Applications</h3>
<ol>
<li><strong>Limit Social Media</strong><br>I minimize my social media presence and avoid sharing unnecessary personal information online.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Regular Privacy Checks</strong><br>I regularly review privacy settings on my accounts and make sure I’m aware of any changes in policies or tracking mechanisms.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Use Aliases or Disposable Emails</strong><br>I use disposable email addresses for one-time sign-ups to avoid giving out my main email and aliases for sign-us that things that are not important but I will probably return to use.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Use Strong Passwords &amp; 2FA</strong><br>Strong passwords and two-factor authentication are essential for keeping my online accounts secure. I do not have a single repeated password.<br><br></li>
<li><strong>Monitor Data Breaches</strong><br>I use services like "Have I Been Pwned" to check if my information has been compromised in any data breaches. Protonmail and NordVPN automatically checks and informs we if any of my email address/password has been detected in data breaches.</li>
</ol>
<p>These are just some of the steps I have taken that isn't too much of an inconvenience for me to keep my privacy and data secure.</p>
<p>Do let me know if you have any questions or have any suggestions :D </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why Linux is My Daily Driver Now</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-linux-is-my-daily-driver-now/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-linux-is-my-daily-driver-now/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/Screenshot_20250821_201728.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Tech Tools"/>
            <category term="Privacy Journey"/>

        <updated>2025-08-21T18:37:05+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/Screenshot_20250821_201728.png" alt="BASH!" />
                    My First PC - The Compaq Presario My fathers Compaq Presario with Windows 95 - Not original image but exactly how it looked I have been around computers for as long as i can remember*. The first PC i ever touched was a Compaq Presario running Windows 95 with a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/Screenshot_20250821_201728.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="BASH!" /></p>
                <h2>My First PC - The Compaq Presario</h2>
<figure class="post__image align-center" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="outline: 3px solid rgba(var(--color-primary-rgb), 0.55) !important;" src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/compaqpresario.jpg" alt="Compaq Presario running Windows 95" width="889" height="500" sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/compaqpresario-xs.jpg 300w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/compaqpresario-sm.jpg 480w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/compaqpresario-md.jpg 768w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/compaqpresario-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<figcaption >My fathers Compaq Presario with Windows 95 - Not original image but exactly how it looked</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I have been around computers for as long as i can remember<span style="color: #e03e2d;">*</span>. The first PC i ever touched was a Compaq Presario running Windows 95 with a 56kbps dial-up connection. I can still hear the sound of the modem connecting like it was yesterday. At that time, the internet was still young as was I. It was a vast uncharted world and the PC was my gateway into it. From internet explorer browsing random sites to flash games to hanging out on telnet BBS (bulletin board system) to simple coding, learning how drivers worked, thinkering with things and some curious hacking (shuting down teacher's PC remotely using CMD, making some "small" changes to the school's website). Those early days sparked a deep curiosity in me about how the systems operated but mainly how they could be manipulated.</p>
<p>*I'm not that old, I just started young.</p>
<h2>The Lead Up to Using Linux</h2>
<p>Fast forward a few years, I started exploring other OSes (Operating Systems) such as Linux and the many distros (Distributions) such as Debian, Fedora, Ubuntu, Arch, PopOS! etc. Since then, I have always had a dual-boot setup, Linux system as my secondary boot as I always fall back to Windows as their GUI (Graphical User Interface) always made things easier and also for better gaming compatibility. However, over the years, Linux has really improved in all departments, from GUI to gaming support (some games even perform better on Linux now).</p>
<p>As I grew older and followed how the internet and technology has grown. The internet that was once an open space for freedom, sharing and exploration isn't what it used to be anymore. It has became a place for data harvesting, targeted ads and constant surveillance. The more i found out how it all works, the more i wanted to protect my own data and also help others do the same. With that said, that's how my privacy journey began.</p>
<h3>Digital Minimalism to Privacy Advocate</h3>
<h6>Minimalism</h6>
<p>A few years ago, I noticed that I spent hours just playing mindless games on my mobile phone, doom scrolling social media and checking my notifications every few minutes. I decided it was time to try out digital minimalism for a few months. I challenged myself to remove unnecessary distractions, which meant deactivating the few social media accounts I used only keeping Instagram to connect with friends and to occasionally see what they're up to. No more than 1 hour of use per day.</p>
<p>Doing this, I have actually freed up time and space for deeper and more meaningful interactions with technology and even the people around me. What I thought was an experiment for a few months lasted longer than expected. I never went back to social media again.</p>
<p>Sidenote: Now that I use my mobile phone less, I notice how much people are using theirs during dinners and meet-ups, it's <strong>FUCKING</strong> annoying. Might as well just hangout on Discord.</p>
<h6>Privacy Advocate</h6>
<p>During my digital minimalism journey, I also realized how much information and data we give away without thinking about it. From sharing everything we do to tracking cookies to social media surveillance. The technology that I once loved for connecting has evolved into exploiting us. We have became the product of these mega corporations, profiting off our data.</p>
<p>That was when I decided to dive into the world of privacy advocacy, learning about data encryption, VPN's and opensource tools that would help secure my data and minimize my digital footprint. This lead me to moving away from big tech such as Google, Amazon &amp; Microsoft etc. Obviously, there is no way to 100% avoid them, but it'll try my best to minimize contact. That's also the driving reason I have moved away from Windows and made Linux my main OS.</p>
<h3>Making the Switch</h3>
<p>I was lucky to have started tinkering with Linux since the early stages so I have some knowledge, making the learning curve less steep. However, Linux today is far more user friendly, it might even be easier to use than Windows now.</p>
<p>For over a decade, I have always kept Linux with me in a dual-boot configuration but it was always my secondary OS. As I started to embrace privacy more fully, I realized that Windows no longer align with my values. It's time to make Linux my primary OS and Windows my second boot option.</p>
<p>Why not just remove Windows completely? </p>
<p>The only reason I still keep Windows around is for gaming. Many games with strong anti cheat does not support Linux. So, I only boot into Windows then I needa game.</p>
<h3>Why Linux?</h3>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/Screenshot_20250821_201237.png" alt="My Fedora KDE Desktop" width="1920" height="1080" sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Screenshot_20250821_201237-xs.png 300w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Screenshot_20250821_201237-sm.png 480w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Screenshot_20250821_201237-md.png 768w ,https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Screenshot_20250821_201237-lg.png 1024w">
<figcaption >My Fedora KDE Desktop</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As a privacy advocate, I now value privacy, autonomy and control over my data and digital life. Linux was the way to go.</p>
<p>After years of trying countless Linux Distros (Debian, Fedora, Ubuntu, Arch, Mint, Gentoo etc) with countless desktop environment (Gnome, KDE, Hyprland etc.).</p>
<p>All of these Linux distros has their own pros and cons but they have one thing in common: better privacy compared to Windows. Ultimately, I have chosen to settle down with Fedora KDE as it aligns with my values</p>
<p>Fedora KDE being opensource means I have full control over my system and security. I can see what's happening under the hood, no surveillance or data collection. My PC and data now belongs to me and me alone.</p>
<p>Also, most applications I use on Windows are available on Linux or an alternative exists. *More on this in another post.</p>
<p>TL;DR:</p>
<ul>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="7226" data-end="7259">Focus on Privacy and Security</strong><br data-start="7259" data-end="7262">Fedora support on free software and security was another big reason I chose it. Unlike Windows, where I had to fight to keep my data private, Fedora comes strong build in privacy tools and security features like SELinux, regular updates, and strong encryption support. Definitely a more secure environment for someone who values privacy.</p>
</li>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="6679" data-end="6720">Up to Date Software</strong><br data-start="6720" data-end="6723">Fedora always provides the latest stable software without all the unnecessary bloat that comes with other systems like Windows. I get cutting edge features and tools without compromising on performance or security.</p>
</li>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="6932" data-end="6957">KDEs Customizability</strong><br data-start="6957" data-end="6960">I can tweak everything from the look and feel of the desktop. This level of customization allows me to make the system my own, exactly how I want it to work and how I want my workflow to be</p>
</li>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="3300" data-end="3331">Telemetry &amp; Data Collection</strong><br data-start="3331" data-end="3334">As a privacy advocate, the amout of data Windows harvested even with privacy settings adjusted to the maximum, I knew there was no way to fully escape the telemetry and tracking. The amount of private things we do on our personal PC daily should remain only for us to know about.</p>
</li>
<li data-start="7223" data-end="7602">
<p data-start="7226" data-end="7602"><strong data-start="3980" data-end="4009">No Bloatware &amp; Unwanted Apps</strong><br data-start="4009" data-end="4012">Windows seemed to be increasingly bloated with apps that I do not want or need. Things like OneDrive, Cortana, and other Microsoft services reminded me of how little control I have over my own PC.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">I have been using Fedora exclusively since the start of 2025 while only booting into Windows for gaming. I couldn't be happier.  My PC now respects my privacy, gives me full control, and works on my terms not on the terms of big corporations.</p>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">Check out <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Fedora Project</a> if you are interested.</p>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">Stay tuned for my future posts, perhaps on what privacy tools I use and what applications I use as an alternative if they are unavailble on Linux.</p>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">As usual, you know where to find me if you wanna join the privacy journey or have any questions regarding these topics.</p>
<p data-start="7971" data-end="8201">Thanks for reading! :D</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why I choose full-time &quot;Unemployment&quot;</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-i-choose-full-time-unemployment/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/why-i-choose-full-time-unemployment/</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/14/Screenshot_20250818_151032-2.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Reflections"/>
            <category term="In-my-opinion"/>
            <category term="Finance"/>

        <updated>2025-08-18T16:49:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/14/Screenshot_20250818_151032-2.png" alt="" />
                    Okay, it was supposed to be a short post, but I locked in and didn't notice I was typing so much. lol I've had it with these mfking people saying this mfking sentence: "Go get a real job." When people and by people, I mean family and friends ask me&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.alaskantf.com/media/posts/14/Screenshot_20250818_151032-2.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Okay, it was supposed to be a short post, but I locked in and didn't notice I was typing so much. lol</p>
<h3>"Get a Real Job" Nonsense</h3>
<p>I've had it with these mfking people saying this mfking sentence: "Go get a real job."</p>
<p>When people and by people, I mean family and friends ask me "What do you do?" and I mention that I’m unemployed and prefer not to have a full time job, they often look at me like I'm batshit crazy. Well, sometimes I do think I AM crazy.</p>
<h3>Background Story:</h3>
<p>I was never the default citizen.</p>
<p class="msg msg--success">Study hard → get the paper → land a job → pay taxes → get married → buy a house → die.</p>
<p>In school, I was probably the “meh” below-average student. Things were too structured and boring. My answers would be marked wrong even if the final answer was correct because I used a different way to solve it. Most of the times, I just got it totally wrong lel. Still, I passed just enough to move on, which was fine by me. Not gonna waste my energy on something I'm not interested in,</p>
<p>After studies, like every generic citizen here, I served in the military. That went smoothly, nothing much to say. Then came university, where I majored in Economics. Again, just an average student. No "magna cum anything laude." LOL.</p>
<p><strong>So why Economics?</strong></p>
<p>Two words: <strong>Stock.</strong> <strong>Market.</strong></p>
<p>I always had an interest in the market since the Great Recession and the invention of Bitcoin in 2008–2009. (I was a computer geek, story for another post.)</p>
<p>I started trading/investing in equities in 2016. It’s like a video game: don’t run out of credits, and try to beat the high score. I LOVE IT.</p>
<h3>My Brief 9-to-5 Life and Epiphany</h3>
<p>After graduation, I went on a little soul-searching trip (backpacked and made many questionable financial choices), then got a job.</p>
<p>Every day, it was:</p>
<ul>
<li>"Looking" stressed about KPIs (which I didn’t take seriously, of course. I ain’t here to build your dream, I’m here to take your money and build mine.)</li>
<li>Useless micromanagement from clueless higher-ups who know shit and think "synergy" is a personality trait.</li>
<li>Wake up at 6:30am, work all day, then try to trade U.S. markets from 9:30pm to 4:00am.</li>
</ul>
<p>Remember people, life is too short to stress over nonsense because:</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight">If it can be done, get it done. If it can’t be done, why stress?</p>
<p>After some quick calculations, I realized I made about the same or more in the market compared to my day job (before taxes). And where I live, capital gains are <strong>non-taxable</strong>.</p>
<p>The 9-to-5 wasn’t just soul-sucking it was killing my portfolio. Trading the U.S. market (9:30pm–4:00am) while waking up at 6:30am to prep for work?</p>
<p><strong>My quality of life was:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sleep: <strong>Fucked</strong></li>
<li>Freedom: <strong>None</strong></li>
<li>Returns: <strong>Minimal</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>So I stayed there for a year since the pay was decent for a fresh grad, but really, I was just there to leech their money and fuck off which I did gracefully, like a polite thief. I added the earnings to my portfolio, gave it a nice boost, and never looked back.</p>
<p>Now, I am full-time unemployed, a job I love. Some days are chill, some are stressful AF. But:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rest when I want</li>
<li>Work at my peak hours</li>
<li>No one to bug me</li>
<li>Travel freely as long as I’ve got my laptop and internet</li>
<li>Watch a movie/game/chat with friends while monitoring markets on chill days</li>
<li>You get it.</li>
</ul>
<p>BTW, the stressful days are AWESOME! It keeps me in check, on my feet and prevent complacency.</p>
<h3>Salary VS My Unemployment</h3>
<p>Let’s base the numbers on a $100K annual income. You can change the numbers and the outcome would be the same as they are in percentages.</p>
<p><strong>Mr. 9-to-5 Salaryman</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Annual Salary: +$100,000</li>
<li>20% Sovereign Fund Contribution: -$20,000 (To be returned when? God knows, it keeps moving further away.)</li>
<li>17% Employer Top-up to Sovereign Fund: +$17,000</li>
<li>Income Tax: -$5,650</li>
</ul>
<p>Total Compensation: $100,000 + $17,000 = $117,000<br>Take-Home: $100,000 - $20,000 - $5,650 = $74,350<br>Locked in Sovereign Fund (aka Narnia): $37,000 (Growing at ~4% per annum)</p>
<p><strong>Me – The Allegedly "Unemployed"</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Annual Income: +$100,000</li>
<li>Sovereign Fund Contribution: -$0</li>
<li>Employer Top-up: +$0</li>
<li>Income Tax: -$0</li>
</ul>
<p>Total Compensation: $100,000<br>Take-Home: $100,000<br>Locked in Sovereign Fund: $0</p>
<p>Let's not forget about the power of compounding in the market.</p>
<p>Mr Salaryman would be getting $117000 per year.</p>
<p>The unemployedman would be getting ($100,000 + gain%) and then (total from previous year + gains%) repeated yearly.</p>
<p>That's just a rough calculation.</p>
<h3>But the Benefits! The Stability! The “Buy House!”</h3>
<p>According to the default citizens, they make $17,000 more than me and have $37,000 in the sovereign fund earning ~4% per year.</p>
<p>Here’s my POV: Yep, you made $17,000 more but your $37,000 is locked up until you either buy a house and empty it doing so, reach the ever shifting retirement age, or die and pass it to your kids.</p>
<p>I take home $25,650 more than you and reinvest it into a portfolio that returned ~80% annually (versus your fund’s 4%).</p>
<p>So being unemployed gives me more liquidity, no tax, and the freedom to top up my sovereign fund <strong>if</strong> I ever feel like buying a house. (CPF should never be reason for buying a house, unless you agree that you require someone a.k.a government to babysit your spending habits.) Either way, it's probably impossible to buy a house here without getting cuffed or locked down for life. But stability, ah, the illusion of it. We’ll get into that a little later.</p>
<h3>TL;DR – Why I'm Not Chained to a Desk</h3>
<p>I’m not unemployed because <strong>I can’t get a job</strong>. (I haven’t checked. Maybe I can't. LOL.)</p>
<p>I’m unemployed because <strong>I already have a job, </strong>one that:</p>
<ul>
<li>Pays well (in my opinion, really subjective)</li>
<li>No uncomfortable office wear</li>
<li>Unlimited breaks</li>
<li>More time with family and friends</li>
<li>Hobbies such as the <a href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/my-projects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">projects</a> i'm working on</li>
<li>Not taxed to oblivion (Income already taxed and our taxed income is than taxed again; GST, road tax, property tax etc. Cmon bruh.)</li>
</ul>
<p>So to everyone who keeps telling me to “get a real job”:</p>
<p class="msg msg--success msg--highlight msg--warning">I have one. It’s just not the kind you can flex on LinkedIn.</p>
<h3>Final Thoughts</h3>
<p>I’d agree stability is an issue. But I’ve never seen stability stop death from coming.</p>
<p>We plan, save, insure, and settle and then one day, we vanish. I’d rather live with uncertainty than die having played it safe.</p>
<p>Risk keeps me awake. The unknown keeps me on my feet. Security might help you live longer, but curiosity is what makes you feel alive now.</p>
<p>I’ve always believed in the present. The past is gone. The future might never come. So what else is there but now?</p>
<h4>Random thoughts:</h4>
<p>The government always says we have to work hard for the future generation, for the future of the country. But when exactly do we get to enjoy ourselves?</p>
<p>We build the present and live the present. Let the future generation build and enjoy theirs.</p>
<p>Because if every generation is only building for the next, here’s what happens: each generation ends up living off the previous ones and nothing truly progresses. It’s just sacrifice passed down like an heirloom, and nobody gets to celebrate. That's probably what all government wants, mindless people, under their control with the illusion of control.</p>
<p>Thank you for reading.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hello, world!</title>
        <author>
            <name>AlaskanTF(ATF)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.alaskantf.com/hello-world/"/>
        <id>https://blog.alaskantf.com/hello-world/</id>
            <category term="Travel Journal"/>
            <category term="Tech Tools"/>
            <category term="Reflections"/>
            <category term="Privacy Journey"/>
            <category term="Guides/How-To"/>
            <category term="Gaming"/>

        <updated>2025-08-06T13:36:24+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Just a test post.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Just a test post.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
